Alexandru Dinca



dnkalex@gmail.com



+40721766484



linkedin.com/in/deneka

Summary

As a skilled Full Stack Web Developer and experienced Product & Project Manager, I have a demonstrated history of success in the IT industry.

With over 10 years of experience in developing, maintaining and managing web applications and projects, I possess a deep understanding of web technologies and a proactive approach to problem-solving.

My strong analytical skills, emotional intelligence, and ability to lead cross-functional teams have proven to be valuable assets in delivering successful projects.

I excel in project management, with proficiency in Agile methodologies and a thorough understanding of business requirements. My technical documentation skills, problem-solving abilities, and exceptional communication make me a valuable asset to any team.

I am always looking for new challenges and opportunities to grow as a manager and professional.

Experience



Development & Delivery Manager

CustomSoft

Apr 2020 - Present (2 years 10 months)

- Main point of contact regarding technical discussions between CustomSoft & VTEX while also ensuring timely and quality deliverables.
- Understanding and representing end customer needs while maintaining a close collaboration with VTEX first party app core team in order to ensure alignment with their internal roadmap.
- In charge with new technology adoption inside the organization and the successful delivery of customer projects.
- Conducted business analysis for every new onboarded customer to identify pain points and possible bottlenecks in the development of the project.
- Defined and implemented on boarding procedures and delivery of BigCommerce projects.
- Worked closely with the Sales department offering support and facilitating contract signing by bringing a technical guidance to the end customer.



Research And Development Manager

CymbloT

Jul 2019 - Apr 2020 (10 months)

- Organized successfully new implementation workflows using backlogs, changelogs, sprints, code review and QA procedures.
- Led the development team composed of 6 DEVs (2 FE, 4 BE) and 2 QAs in close collaboration with the Romanian Chief Technical Officer and Israeli Product Manager.
- Responsibilities included managing and prioritizing the product backlog, translating product manager's strategies to epics & tasks for development.

• Worked closely with the development team in order to achieve roadmap goals.

Chief Technology Officer

CustomSoft

Oct 2017 - Jun 2019 (1 year 9 months)

- Defined product roadmaps for two in-house products and collaborated with Sales team for upcoming strategies and new features.
- Revised existing development procedures and successfully implemented new workflows.
- Managed a team of 10 DEVs, 2 QAs, 3 PMs.
- Empowered PMs to better organize their projects and be autonomous while also overviewing career paths for each of the DEVs and QAs.

Software Developer

CustomSoft

Dec 2016 - Jun 2019 (2 years 7 months)

IT Project Manager

CustomSoft

Dec 2016 - Jun 2019 (2 years 7 months)

Software Developer

State Institution

Jun 2013 - Dec 2016 (3 years 7 months)

Web Developer

Custom-Web

Apr 2012 - Oct 2016 (4 years 7 months)

Education



Military Technical Academy "Ferdinand I"

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science

2009 - 2013

Carol I Craiova

High school degree, Mathematics and Computer Science 2005 - 2009

Skills

Analytical Skills • Emotional Intelligence • Cross-functional Team Leadership • Business Requirements • Problem Solving • Technical Documentation • Agile Methodologies • Communication • Project Management • Software Development